Well.
글쎄요
Hi there, this is time for PC people to get set up.
안녕하세요, PC 사람들이 준비될 시간이에요. Get up
So all you Mac people out there, you don't need to be watching this one.
맥을 좋아하는 분들은 이걸 안 봐도 돼요
And now's the time when I tell you guys that I told the Mac people that they were my favorite people
이제 말씀드릴 차례입니다 Mac 사람들에게 제가 좋아하는 사람들이라고 했어요 제가
because I'm a mac user myself, but you know, I am a mac user.
Mac 사용자니까요 하지만 Mac 사용자 맞아요
But I'll have you know that I started out in PCs.
하지만 난 PC로 시작했어요
I in fact worked for IBM for a few years.
IBM 밑에서 몇 년 일했죠
So really, in my heart of hearts, I'm from a IBM from PC blood.
전 PC 혈통의 IBM 출신이에요
So.
그래서요?
So you guys are really my people no matter what I said to the other people.
내가 다른 사람들한테 뭐라고 하든 당신들은 내 사람이에요
Anyways, let's get you set up with a PC to use the environment that we need for this entire course.
어쨌든, 전체 과정을 위해 필요한 환경을 사용하도록 PC로 get 설정하죠
So we start by going to the repository, my repository for this class, LM engineering, which is at
저장소로 가서 시작하죠 이 클래스를 위한 제 저장소요 LM 엔지니어링, 깃허브에
github.com slash my name LM engineering.
있죠 내 이름 LM 엔지니어링이요
This link should be all over the place in the course and in the in the notes for the course and resources
이 링크는 코스 곳곳에 있어야 합니다 코스 노트와 리소스 등에도요
And when you go there, you see this repository on GitHub.
깃허브에 이 저장소가 있어요
And if you scroll down you get to see the Readme file that I've written with setup instructions, and
스크롤을 내리면 Settingation 지시와 함께 작성한 리드메 파일
I hope I've done a decent job in laying out all of the steps required to set up your environment.
보이시죠 여러분 환경을 셋업하는 데 필요한 모든 단계를 잘 배치했길 바라요
And if you prefer to follow instructions that way, then do it that way rather than watching the video.
그렇게 지시를 따르는 게 좋다면 영상을 보는 대신 그렇게 하세요
And hopefully I've done it well.
제가 잘 해냈길 바라요
And if you find a problem with them, please, please let me know so I can update them for everybody
문제가 있으면 저한테 알려 주세요 제가 대신 업데이트해 드릴게요
Anyway, if you do go through these instructions, what you'll find is that the first thing it says
어쨌든 이 설명서를 훑어보면 제일 먼저 나오는 게 PC 사용자에게는
is that for PC people, you may need to install git.
git을 설치해야 한다는 거예요
If you've not done it before.
처음이라면 말이죠
Git the code control system, something that I imagine most of you who have used some might not.
코드 컨트롤 시스템을 깃으로 해요 사용해 보신 분은 잘 모르시겠지만요
It comes installed on Macs by default, but not on windows.
기본값으로 Macs에 설치되지만 윈도우에는 없어요
And so if you follow this link, you get to the git download page, you follow the instructions to download,
이 링크를 따라가면 Git 다운로드 페이지로 가서 다운로드 설명서를
and you then have to say okay about 20 times and just accept the defaults for everything.
따라가면 스무 번 정도 확인을 누르고 모든 기본값을 수락해야 해요
I just went through and did this myself when I was pressing.
다림질할 때 제가 직접 했어요
Okay, okay, okay, so go through all of those things, just take the defaults all the way through
좋아요, 좋아요, 그런 걸 모두 검토하세요 기본값만 끝까지요
and you will install git on your computer.
그럼 컴퓨터에 git을 설치할 수 있어요
And so once you have done that come back to the repository.
그렇게 하고 나면 저장소로 돌아와요
The next thing to do is at the top here there's this green button code.
다음으로 할 일은 여기 위에 녹색 버튼 코드가 있어요
And if you press that green button, it comes up here with the link to the repository.
녹색 버튼을 누르면 저장소로 가는 링크와 함께 여기 뜨죠
And you can pick either of these.
둘 중 하나를 고르세요
But we were going to pick this https one.
Https 1을 선택할게요
And we're going to press um actually you should pick this one and then press the copy button to copy
우리가 누를 것은 사실 이걸 선택해야 해요 그리고 복사 버튼을 눌러 클립보드로
it to clipboard.
복사하세요
What we're now going to do is we're going to go and open a new PowerShell.
이제 할 것은 새 PowerShell을 여는 거예요
Uh, let me see.
어디 봐요
Type PowerShell in here.
PowerShell을 입력하세요
I'm a little bit clumsy at the PC because it has been a little while since I've done this, so you may
PC에선 제가 좀 서툴러요 이걸 해본 지 좀 됐거든요 제가 바보짓을 해도
have to bear with me if I make a fool of myself.
여러분이 참아주셔야 할지도 몰라요
But there we go.
하지만 됐어요
Up comes the PowerShell.
PowerShell이 나오네요
Um.
네
And now the first thing you need to do, which you may already have, is create a projects directory,
가장 먼저 해야 할 일은 이미 갖고 계실지도 모르지만 프로젝트 디렉터리를 만드는 겁니다
something that where your different projects that you work on will go.
작업하는 다양한 프로젝트가 가는 곳이죠
You may already have a projects directory, but if I do CD projects, it turns out I do not.
프로젝트 디렉터리가 이미 있을 수도 있지만 CD 프로젝트를 하면 없을 수도 있어요
So I can make a projects directory by doing this.
이렇게 해서 프로젝트 디렉터리를 만들 수 있어요
You may also just use the Windows Explorer.
Windows 탐색기를 사용해도 되고요
Uh, the the File Explorer if you prefer.
파일 익스플로러라고도 하죠
You don't need to use the command prompt, but, uh, is he doing that?
명령 프롬프트는 필요 없지만 그렇게 하고 있나요?
So I've made a new projects directory in my home directory.
가정 디렉터리에 새 프로젝트 디렉터리를 만들었죠
I'm now going to CD into it, and here we are in our projects directory, which of course is empty or
이제 CD로 들어가겠습니다 프로젝트 디렉터리에 왔어요 물론 비어 있죠, dir요 원한다면
dir, if you prefer, the windows way.
Windows 방식이요
Uh, what I now type is very simple.
지금 입력하는 건 아주 간단해요
Uh, it is git clone, uh, which means I want to make a local copy of this repository, and then you
아, Git 클론입니다. 어… 이 저장소의 로컬 복사본을 만들고 싶다는 의미입니다.
put in the name of the repository, the link to it that we copied a second ago.
그리고 저장소의 이름을 적습니다. 조금 전에 복사한 링크요.
Uh, and when we do that, it will immediately download.
그러면 바로 다운로드 돼요
It's already happened.
이미 벌어진 일이에요
All the code has been cloned to my local drive.
모든 코드가 제 로컬 드라이브로 복제됐어요
So if I look here, you'll see that there is indeed a folder called LM engineering that we will now
여길 보시면 LM 엔지니어링이라는 폴더가 있는 게 보이시죠 이제 들어가볼
go into.
거예요
And there is all of the code that will be our playground for the next eight weeks.
앞으로 8주간은 이 코드가 우리 놀이터가 되겠죠
And now it's worth mentioning that sometimes people use the expression the project root directory to
가끔 사람들이 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리라는 표현을 이 폴더 LM 엔지니어링을 의미한다고
mean this folder LM engineering.
말할 필요가 있어요
It is the root directory of this project.
이 프로젝트의 루트 디렉터리예요
So if I ever say verbally, or if it's in the in the readme that it mentions project root.
제가 말로 하거나 리드미에 프로젝트 루트를 언급하면요
I'm talking about this directory LM engineering.
디렉터리 LM 엔지니어링 말이에요
There we are.
됐어요
So the next step is now to install Anaconda, which is as I say, it's a it's a reasonably heavyweight
다음 단계는 아나콘다를 설치하는 겁니다 말씀드렸듯이 아나콘다는 아주
tool because it's super powerful.
강력한 도구예요
And the place to do that is back in the the Readme again, there is a link to where you go to install
다시 리드미로 돌아가서 하면 됩니다 아나콘다를 설치하는 곳으로 가는 링크가
Anaconda and there it is.
있어요 저기 있네요
And I have that up over here.
여기 위에 있어요
Um, except the cookies.
쿠키만 빼고요
This is the Anaconda documentation for installing on windows, and it tries to get you to give your
윈도우에 설치를 위한 아나콘다 문서화입니다 이메일 주소와 다른 여러 가지를
email address and various other things which you can feel free to do if you wish.
제공하도록 합니다 원하면 자유롭게 할 수 있어요
But then at the end, you can also just say what we'll do now press the download.
하지만 마지막에 우리가 뭘 할 건지 말할 수도 있어요 다운로드를 누르세요
It suggests you could you could provide an email, but you can also just say skip registration here
이메일을 제공할 수도 있지만 원하면 등록을 건너뛰라고 할 수도
if you'd prefer.
있어요
And then you get to this Download Now page.
그럼 Get Now 다운로드 페이지가 나오죠
And this is the download that we will do now.
이제 다운로드 할 거예요
Anaconda is quite large.
아나콘다는 꽤 커요
This is a five gigabyte download.
5기가바이트 다운로드예요
And so it may be something which you don't have the room for.
그래서 공간이 부족할 수도 있어요
And you may also find that this is too heavy weight.
너무 무겁다는 걸 아실 수도 있어요
And there is the alternative approach using virtualenv that I will record after this, which is a simpler
virtualenv를 이용한 다른 접근법이 있습니다. 이것은 더 간단한 접근법이지만
approach, but it's less guaranteed to be compatible.
호환성이 보장되지는 않아요.
And, you know, it's less hardcore.
less 하드코어죠
If you want to be a hardcore LM engineer, you should at least try the Anaconda route.
노련한 달 착륙선 엔지니어가 되려면 아나콘다 항로라도 시도해 봐야죠
So you press the download button, which I already did.
다운로드 버튼을 누르세요 제가 이미 했죠
It then brings up a screen to install Anaconda, the usual installation wizard thing, and you have
아나콘다를 설치하기 위한 스크린이 나타납니다 일반적인 설치 마법사죠 예를 몇
to press yes a few times.
번 눌러야 해요
It does prompt you for where you want it to install.
어디에 설치할지 유도하는 거죠
Some people have selected there to install it to a different drive to make sure that you have capacity.
어떤 사람들은 용량이 충분한지 확인하기 위해 다른 드라이브에 설치하도록 선택했어요
Um, and then when that is done, it will complete the installation, take a few minutes to download
그게 끝나면 설치가 완료됩니다 다운로드 후 설치하는
and install, and you will have the Anaconda program on your computer.
데 몇 분 걸리죠 그럼 컴퓨터에 아나콘다 프로그램이 있어요
And what does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이죠?
Well, the thing that it means, as far as we're concerned is that whilst we have this PowerShell that
우리가 아는 한 그 의미는 우리가 아주 익숙한 PowerShell이
we are very familiar with, there is also a new thing on our start menu, which is called Anaconda PowerShell
있는 동안 시작 메뉴에 새로운 것도 있다는 겁니다 아나콘다 PowerShell이란 건데 열어보면
and that if we open it looks very similar, looks just like a normal PowerShell, but it is in fact
아주 비슷해 보여요 일반 PowerShell과 비슷하지만 실은 특별한
a special Anaconda one.
아나콘다죠
Try and expand this window for you.
이 창문을 넓혀볼게요
Hold on a second while I fumble fumble, fumble.
잠깐만요, 공을 놓쳤어요
Uh uh.
네
Now what have I done?
내가 무슨 짓을 한 거죠?
There we go.
됐어요
I'm hopeless at this.
전 가망이 없어요
So the way that you know that it's an Anaconda PowerShell is that this word base appears to the left,
아나콘다 파워셸인지 아는 방법은 왼쪽에 베이스가 보이는 거죠 그 말은 우리가
which means that we are in a world, uh, a base world, rather than in a world that we have built,
베이스 세계에 있다는 겁니다 우리가 만든 세계나 특정 환경을 위한
especially for an environment.
세계가 아니라요
All right.
좋아요
So now I'm going to go into our projects folder that we just made, and I'm going to go into LM engineering.
이제 방금 만든 프로젝트 폴더로 가보겠습니다 LM 엔지니어링으로 가보죠
There it is.
저기 있네요
So we're now in the project root directory as I explained is the right term for it.
이제 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리에 들어왔어요 제가 설명드린 대로요
And I'm now going to run a simple command which is conda which is the name for running anaconda commands.
이제 간단한 명령을 실행할게요 콘다라는 명령어인데 아나콘다 명령을 실행하는 이름이죠
Env which means environment create.
환경 창조를 뜻하죠
I want to create a new environment minus f means I'm going to specify a file which describes exactly
새 환경을 생성하기 위해 마이너스 f는 파일을 명시한다는 의미입니다 이 환경에서 필요한
everything that I need for this environment.
모든 것을 설명하는 거죠
And the file is called Environment.
그 파일은 환경이라고 해요
Environment.
환경이요
Dot YAML.
도트 YAML요
And you can see Environment.yml right right here.
환경을 볼 수 있어요 yml이 여기 있네요
So that is what I'm going to do.
그래서 그렇게 하려고요
Now at this point you will need to go and get a coffee and maybe even two coffees.
이제 가서 커피를 사 오세요 Get you get you, for 두 잔도요
So it does take a bit of time to install this full environment the first time.
비트 전체 환경을 처음 설치하는 데 시간이 좀 걸려요
So when I do it, it's probably takes a few minutes because I've done it before.
몇 분 걸릴 거예요 전에 해 봤거든요
The very first time, it might take somewhere between 10 minutes and 20 minutes depending on your internet
처음 할 때는 인터넷 연결에 따라 다르지만 10분에서 20분 정도
connection, and that's going to be a thing to look out for.
걸립니다 이 정도도 조심해야 해요
So what it's actually doing.
실제로 뭘 하는 거죠?
So it's looking at all of the packages that we say that we need for this data science environment.
이 데이터 과학 환경에 필요하다고 말하는 모든 패키지를 보고 있어요
And it then figures out for this particular type of system, whatever chip you've got and for the various
그러면 이 특정 유형의 시스템을 파악합니다 칩이 무엇이든 다양한 구성이 있습니다 모든 패키지의
configurations that you've got, what are the compatible versions of every single package that we need
호환 가능한 버전이 무엇인지를 파악합니다 미래에는 객체 데이터베이스가
to do things like in the future we'll have an object database, we'll be using Lang chain, we'll be
있을 것입니다 랭체인을 이용할 것입니다 그러디오를 이용할
using gradio all sorts of things.
것입니다 모든 것들이요
It makes sure that we pick the latest versions that are all compatible with each other and also compatible
서로 호환 가능하고 프로세서와 호환 가능한 최신 버전을 선택하도록
with your processor and so on.
하죠
And that's why it now says solving environment.
그래서 환경 해결이라고 하는 거죠
That's the equation that it's solving with lots of different decisions to make.
여러 가지 결정을 내리면서 풀어야 하는 방정식이죠
So it's going to make those decisions.
그런 결정을 내리죠
And it's then going to install all of those packages on your computer.
그런 다음 컴퓨터에 모든 패키지를 설치하죠
And we're going to I'm going to keep keep going with this sentence for a bit longer to see if it's going
이 문장을 좀 더 길게 계속 진행해서 마무리할 수 있을지 보겠습니다.
to get close to wrapping up.
비트 주세요.
Otherwise I might have to, uh, to to break and come back in just a second.
안 그러면 잠시 쉬었다가 다시 와야 할 거예요
All right.
좋아요
It looks like it's going to take just a couple more minutes.
몇 분 더 걸릴 것 같아요
So I'm going to pause the video and I will return when this is ready.
비디오를 일시 정지하고 준비되면 돌아오죠
Well it's just as well I didn't hang on in there.
거기서 안 버틴 게 다행이죠
It took another five minutes from that point to finish.
거기서 결승선까지 5분이 더 걸렸죠
So that would've been an embarrassing amount of five minutes of my waffle that I've rescued you from.
하마터면 5분 동안 와플을 못 먹게 될 뻔했네요
So anyway, this can take a few minutes and I've got a fast connection, as I say, so.
몇 분 걸릴 수도 있어요 말했듯이 연결은 빠르죠
So it could well be 20 30 minutes for you.
당신에겐 20분, 30분이 될 수도 있어요
So hang on in there.
조금만 더 버텨요
But but obviously if it takes unspeakably long, then abandon and go to the next video where we will
하지만 말할 수 없이 오래 걸린다면 포기하고 다른 방식으로 하는 다음 비디오로
do it differently.
오세요
But if it's completed, your your Anaconda PowerShell prompt should look something like this.
하지만 완료되면 아나콘다 파워셸 프롬프트는 이런 모습이어야 하죠
It still says base at the end there.
아직도 맨 끝에 베이스라고 쓰여 있어요
And we've created an environment that is known.
그래서 잘 알려진 환경을 만들었어요
It's called LMS.
LMS라고 하죠
That's the name I gave it.
제가 지은 이름이에요
And to now activate that environment, which means to make that be the live world that that Anaconda
이제 그 환경을 활성화하려면 아나콘다가 활동하는 살아 있는 세계로 만들어야
is working within.
해요
You simply type conda, activate LMS and you'll need to run that.
콘다를 입력해 LMS를 활성화하면 그걸 실행해야 하죠
You'll need to any time that you come back to your computer that you want to start everything again
컴퓨터에 다시 접속할 때마다 모든 걸 다시 시작하고 싶을 겁니다
before you you get started, you will need to remember to open up an anaconda prompt and do conda.
get aanaconda 프롬프트를 열어 콘다를 하는 걸 기억하세요
Activate LMS and your clue that it is now working is that you'll see LMS written over here on the left
LMS 활성화 이제 작동한다는 단서는 여기 왼쪽에서 제 프롬프트 왼쪽에서 LMS가
to the left of my prompt, and that is telling me that I have successfully created my Anaconda environment.
작성된 게 보이실 겁니다 성공적으로 아나콘다 환경을 생성했다는 걸 알려주는 거죠
Um, and another way we can do it is that if we type Python minus minus version, it will tell us that
또 다른 방법은 파이썬 마이너스 버전을 입력하면 파이썬 버전은 3이라고
the version of Python we're on is 3.11.1, which is the version, or at least 3.11 is what I specified
알려줄 거예요 11살요 1번, 그게 버전이죠 적어도 3번이요 이 환경을 위해 11을
for this environment.
지정했어요
So we know that we're on exactly the same version of Python, and everything should be compatible.
그래서 우리는 정확히 같은 버전의 파이썬을 사용하고 있고 모든 것이 호환 가능하다는 것을 알죠
And it just remains for me to type these two words Jupyter Lab.
이제 두 단어를 입력하면 돼요 주피터 랩
And this is going to open up the Jupyter environment, which is this data science environment where
그러면 Jupyter 환경이 열립니다 코드에서 효과적으로
we can work really effectively together on code.
함께 작업할 수 있는 데이터 과학 환경이죠
Again, some of you probably know this back to front.
이미 아시는 분들도 계실 거예요
For some people this might be new.
어떤 사람들에겐 새로운 일이겠죠
I press enter.
엔터키를 눌렀어요
It's going to start Jupyter Lab.
주피터 연구소가 시작될 거예요
Uh, up it comes.
위로 올려요
The first time it might prompt you for which browser do you want to open, but then it opens up with
처음엔 어떤 브라우저를 열지 묻겠지만 제 컴퓨터에
Jupyter Lab on my computer with our eight weeks that lies ahead of us and we are good to go.
주피터 랩이 뜨죠 앞으로 8주 동안의 여정이 펼쳐져 있어요
That is the PC instructions.
그게 PC 지침이에요
Hopefully this has all gone well for you.
모든 게 잘 풀렸길 바라요
If it hasn't, please, please reach out to me, let me know and I will get you sorted.
만약 그렇지 않다면 부디 제게 연락하세요 알려 주시면 해결해 드릴게요 Get up
I will see you then for the next video.
그럼 다음 영상에서 만나요